A Guide to the Holywell Hall Horticultural Records, 1760-1829
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Holywell Hall Horticultural Records, 1770-1829, 1760-1829.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 77.2
21 items.
Holywell Hall (Lincolnshire, England)
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1977.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm M-1317.1
Biographical/Historical Information
Holywell is an English estate dating back to the middle ages. In 1732, it was given to Samuel Reynardson by his sister. It is believed that Samuel Reynardson is the one who laid out the gardens at Holywell Hall.
Scope and Content Information
Notes and information gathered by the owner or caretaker of Holywell Hall (Lincolnshire, England), concerning the creation and care of gardens and vineyards. Also includes lists of flowering shrubs, evergreens, perennial plants, and trees; directions for composting orange trees; methods of wood preservation; properties of the "Auricula;" and hand-drawn maps of the Holywell estate.
Names appearing in the collection include Mr. Knight, Mr. Wright, Mr. Reynardson, Lee and Kennedy, Belton, Mr. Pochin, Emphingham Heath, Mr. Pullen, and William Gozna.
Arrangement
Chronologically arranged.
Index Terms
Persons:
Gozna, William.; Heath, Ephingham.; Knight, Mr.; Pochin, Mr.; Pullen, Mr.; Reynardson, Samuel.; Wright, Mr.
Subjects:
Gardening--England-- Lincolnshire.; Horticulture--England--Lincolnshire.; Landscape gardening--England--Lincolnshire.
Titles:
By God's permission, a sure and certain method to prevent the blight in fruit trees against the walls.
Corporate Names:
Holywell Hall (Lincolnshire, England)
Genre and Form Terms:
Maps--England--Lincolnshire.
Contents List
- Directions for construction of grape vine framing, n.d. (Folder 1)
- List of flowering shrubs, Mr. Wright, 1760. (Folder 1)
- Geometric pattern (for vining?), n.d. (Folder 1)
- List of plants ordered, Mr. Reynardson, 1763. (Folder 1)
- List of plants and "hardy shrubs." Lee and Kennedy, 1764. (Folder 1)
- Directions for making Orange Tree Compost. Belton, 1815. (Folder 1)
- Memorandum. Plantations and alterations at "Holywele," 1811-1829. (Folder 1)
- List of evergreen shrubs, perennial plants, and trees, n.d. (Folder 1)
- Methods of wood preservation and three compositions "impenetrable to water." ca. 1768.
- Diagram for construction of a truncated pyramid, n.d. (Folder 1)
- Numbered list of plants and notes on their care, n.d. (Folder 1)
- Shrubage in Holywell Gardens, n.d. (Folder 1)
- "The Properties which constitute a good Auricula," n.d. (Folder 1)
- "Frame for a Pit for Early Grapes." Mr. Pullen, n.d. (Folder 1)
- List of shrubs, evergreens, and trees, n.d. (Folder 1)
- Map of Holywell, n.d., Hand-drawn, 25 x 51 cm. (Oversize 2X)
- Map of Holywell, n.d., Hand-drawn, 13 x 32 cm. (Oversize 1X)
- Map of Holywell, n.d., Hand-drawn, 30 x 48 cm. (Oversize 2X)
- Mr. Pullen, dimensions for a vine pit, n.d. (Folder 2)
- William Gozna broadside: "By God's permission, a sure and certain method to prevent the blight in fruit trees against the walls." n.d., Broadside. 31 x 19 cm. "William Goznet" has been printed at the bottom of the broadside. "Goznet" has been crossed out and "Gozna" written in ink below it. (Folder 2)
- Various notes and diagrams, n.d.